Vijay Anand

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

Location: Chennai, Tamilnadu Email: vijayvjrj@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 9884127840

REACT DEVELOPER

Passionate React Developer with 1 year of experience focusing on clean, maintainable code and responsive UI design. Eager to learn and grow in a collaborative environment while building modern, user-friendly web applications using React, JavaScript, and Tailwind CSS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries : React.js
Frameworks : Tailwind CSS

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

React Developer *Transen Dynamics* Aug 2024 – Present Remote – Perambur, Chennai

Designed and developed dynamic and responsive website using React.js, Tailwind CSS and JavaScript

- Worked on responsive layout design using Flexbox and Grid.
- Gained real-world experience in debugging and version control.

PROJECTS

E-Commerce Website React.js, Tailwind CSS Source Code

- Developed a clean and modern e-commerce website with Cart functionalities
- Built a product page with product filtering, dynamic cart, and quantity updates.
- Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices

Car Selling Website React.js, Tailwind CSS, Framer Motion Source Code

- Built a car selling website with react slider and modern javascript functionalities
- Created a multipages as a single page application using react-router-dom
- Designed with Framer motion animation effects for better user experience

Food website React.js, Tailwind CSS Source Code

- Fully Responsive food website created with the basic **Filtering** functionalities
- Used grid and flexbox for the better layout experience in every screen types

EDUCATION

Sri Ramanujar Engineering College

Electronics and Communications Engg.

Vandalur, Chennai June 2008 – July 2012

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Maintenance Incharge

RR Arasu Caterers

Mar 2019 – July 2024 Remote – Tambaram, Chennai

- As a chief Incharge, Maintained the fast flow of orders from the customers and ensured the quality service
- Maintained a team of service and managed the schedule of orders efficiently
- Made a path to significant profit by providing the positively impacting interactions at the customers